[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
Red Dragon declared war on Lily Cruz,
and she needs her best lieutenant.
[Damian] Your lives are in danger, Camia.
I need to save you from Red Dragon.
[Paterno] I would like you to
meet Miss Mercedes' associate.
You!
Stop her!
Where's the bomb?!
Call the bomb squad,
and evacuate the building.
Do you understand?
Make sure everyone
gets out of this building!
[Emilia] I came here
because I wanted to know
if Mama had anything to do
with the bombing at Aguas Realty.
You'll find out soon enough.
When it's the right time.
Sir. Ma'am.
Sir Arnaldo's gone missing from his room!
We've searched the premises.
Order all of our men to move
if you have to.
Governor, we don't have
full access to that, as of now.
The one time we need to find Arnaldo,
and you're basically powerless.
What can you do? Nothing!
You are no longer in position,
so that's why you cannot do anything now!
[Lily] We can't let things end here.
If that Myla still refuses to talk,
then we'll gather information on our own.
Madam, we cleaned up the mess.
[Diego] He's dead. He was strangled.
[Lily] For now, let's hurry up
and find a lead.
"Mercedes Palacio"?
[Paterno] I also know of an investor
who's interested
in investing in Aguas Realty.
I would like you to meet
Miss Mercedes' associate.
[Lily] You!
You're the one who blew up
the media complex!
That's right!
And I'm here to finish what I started!
[tense music playing]
Let's go, Diego.
Call the police.
Okay.
Hurry.
[tense music playing]
[Anna] U, V…
W…
X, Y, and Z.
Very good!
Okay. Take your seat, Angel.
All right.
Just continue what you're doing,
and later, we'll have
a little exercise, okay?
-[kids] Yes, ma'am.
-Okay.
[voice prompt] The subscriber
cannot be reached.
Please try again later.
[man] Good morning, universe!
[tense music playing]
[Arnaldo] Oh, what a lovely day!
You know what?
You're all the reason
why my mornings are so great.
You make me feel great! Especially you!
I know you give me clean air.
So, thank you.
Lea?
Wasn't that hut abandoned?
[Lea] Yeah, as far as I know.
Do you know that guy standing over there?
[Lea] No. I've never seen him before.
-Okay, thanks anyway.
-All right.
-Please get back to the kids.
-Okay.
You're so beautiful. Just look at you.
What happened to your flowers?
Let me fix them up.
[tense music playing]
Just continue what you're doing.
Because you're making the people
who live here so happy.
Especially me!
[tense music continues]
You too! You're the biggest one here.
You're being a great example
to all of them.
[tense music swelling]
[exhales]
Good morning to everyone!
What a lovely day!
[reporter] A woman hanged herself
in Poblacion Ardiente.
She was later identified
as Carlotta Navarro,
caretaker of businesswoman Ivy Aguas.
[Anna] Nanny Carlotta was like
a mother to me too.
Please don't deny me the chance
to seek justice for her death.
[Arnaldo] I can kill you and make it look
like you committed suicide,
just like what I did to Carlotta.
[Anna] Do you know how long I've waited
for this opportunity?
Anna.
[breathing heavily]
Arnaldo, you monster!
Of all the places I'd see you!
Ah, good morning, friend.
-Friend? You monster!
-Wait! Hold on!
-You're a murderer!
-Hold on, hold on!
-What are you talking about?!
-Give me that!
-Hey! No.
-Give me that.
-No, give it to me.
-I don't know--Give it to me.
-[Anna grunts]
-Hey! Are you all right?
-Don't touch me!
[Arnaldo] Uh--
[pants]
[pensive music swelling]
-You look hurt. Let me see.
-No.
-I just want to--
-No!
Stay away from me!
[pensive music playing]
[Anna gasps]
[wood clatters]
You seem to know who I am.
I know you well enough!
You're Arnaldo Ardiente!
Uh…
Good for you. I don't even know who I am.
[Anna gasps]
-Stay away!
-I won't hurt you.
-Don't come near me!
You see…
I don't know what you were talking about.
I don't remember anything.
I don't know what happened,
but I've been told that I got sick,
so I can't remember a thing now.
People keep telling me of all
the wrong things I've done.
So if you're one of the people…
that I've wronged before…
I want to ask for forgiveness.
I hope you can forgive me.
-[Camia] Does it hurt?
-[Anna] No.
-There you go.
-Thank you, Auntie.
[Camia] It's nothing.
Anna, what happened to you?
She just tripped earlier, Jepoy.
And you? Where were you?
We were all worried.
I've been trying to contact you.
Where have you been?
Going around town.
You should've been more careful.
-[Camia] It's done.
-[Anna] Thanks, Auntie.
Lily, Diego, how did it go?
We need to be cautious, Mom.
[tense music playing]
I'm not dealing with just anybody.
Mr. Paterno's dead.
But I got a lead.
Mercedes Palacio.
[eerie music]
I'll find out who that monster is.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Mercedes] All you need to know right now
is that Red Dragon declared war
on Lily Cruz.
And she needs her best lieutenant-- you.
[tense music playing]
Camia, you need to stop Lily.
This is serious!
Lily knows what she's doing, Damian.
They nearly blew her up.
How are you fine with that?
Lily's survived so much worse than that.
These people are on a different level.
She can't win this.
Why, Damian?
Do you know Mercedes Palacio?
No, I don't know her.
But they've shown us all
that they have the firepower
to bring her down.
I know you're worried for my daughter.
But you have to trust her.
Camia, you need to fear them.
Because Lily's already standing
in her own grave.
[Lily] We need to leave now.
Mercedes Palacio took the bait.
She thinks someone's going
to inquire about her business.
But it's just going to be a ruse.
Don't worry.
Diego and the guards will be there.
Keep your eyes open, dear.
I will. Thanks, Mom.
-Bye.
-Lily.
What is it?
Be careful out there.
Mom.
[pensive music playing]
[acoustic music playing]
[Diego] Ivy, I want you to be happy.
I want you to be free of this burden.
And I hope I'll be there with you.
You know how much I love you, right?
[Ivy] Diego, I love you.
["Hindi Kita Iiwan" playing]
Mercedes is on her way.
My people are ready.
[romantic instrumental playing]
It's like there's no end to this fight.
[music continues]
[tense music playing]
That's Mercedes.
Standby, everyone.
[phone ringing]
Madam?
No. [scoffs] I wasn't aware.
I apologize.
Right away, Madam. Thank you.
Change of plans.
Turn the car around. Hurry!
What's going on?
Why is she turning the car around?
[Diego] What's she doing?
Let's go.
[tense music playing]
Make sure to guard the house
and check the security--
She was right there, and we lost her!
Lily, how did it go?
It didn't push through, Mom.
Mercedes Palacio suddenly backed out.
She literally went the other way.
It's like she figured out we were waiting.
But this isn't over yet.
I will stop her.
She'll pay for everything she did to me.
Does it still hurt?
No. I just don't want to overwork it.
What happened to you?
I thought you had bodyguards.
None of them helped you out?
I was alone when this happened.
Why were you alone?
Don't be so stubborn, Anna.
You're in danger as long
as the Ardientes are out there.
I know, Jepoy. But I tripped
because I saw Arnaldo.
Arnaldo?
[Jepoy mumbles]
Anna, be honest with me.
Did Arnaldo do that to you?
-No.
-Did he hurt you?
-No, Jepoy.
-He didn't hurt me.
Tell me the truth.
He didn't do anything to me.
Actually, it seems like he's changed.
[Jepoy] What do you mean?
Anna, a snake may shed its skin,
but it's still a snake.
Do you think I'm stupid?
I know how dangerous he is.
And I thought the same way too.
But when I saw him,
the way he moved and spoke…
-He seemed crazy.
-He always was.
That's not what I mean, Jepoy.
He said he doesn't remember
being an Ardiente.
[Jepoy scoffs]
Anna, if the Devil himself
forgot he was a demon…
would you forgive him for all his sins?
I will never, ever forget
that he was the one
who killed Nanny Carlotta.
But, when I saw him, it was like…
it was like he was innocent!
Jepoy, can you actually
punish someone for a crime
they don't remember committing?
[Jepoy] I'll kill him.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Julio] Is everything all right?
Of course, Grandpa.
Everything's all right.
I've never felt better.
You know, it's like a heavy load
was lifted from my heart.
[Ivy] I want to quit politics, Grandpa.
-I want to be a priest.
-[chokes]
[Emilia] Hmm…
So, how does it feel
to be powerless, Papa?
Do you feel now what you made me
feel all these years?
Why, Emilia?
What do you have to pride yourself on?
Nothing yet, Papa.
If you're so proud of that
90-day governor of yours…
Just accept it, Papa.
Governor Mateo Ruiz is the governor
and in power right now.
And, you? You have nothing left.
Oops!
You know, Papa? I forgot to say something.
You're about to become obsolete.
[chuckles]
How dare you!
[somber music playing]
-[Anna cries]
-[Jepoy] Anna!
[Anna] Jepoy.
Jepoy, she's gone, Jepoy. She's gone.
[grunting]
She's gone, Jepoy.
[Jepoy] Nanny, I couldn't protect you.
-[screams]
-[gunshot]
[gasps]
[foreboding music playing]
-[gun cocks]
-Jepoy?
Jepoy, wait!
What are you going to do with that, huh?!
-Hey! Hey! Hey, Anna!
-No!
-Be careful with that!
-Jepoy, no!
-Give me that!
-Give that back.
You know, I should've never
told you about Arnaldo!
Well, it's good you did
'cause I'm going to kill him!
He's not the same person anymore!
Anna, I don't care!
He killed Nanny Carlotta!
And, no matter what,
he's still an Ardiente,
so give me that.
Jepoy, listen to me!
If you kill him,
then that makes you
no different from them!
[Anna] Is that what you want?
Fine, you can have that.
I won't need it to kill the guy, anyway.
-Jepoy, wait!
-What now?!
I said, wait! Just listen to me!
You don't have to hurt Arnaldo.
You can't just let anger
take over your heart, okay?
Listen to me. You are not a murderer.
You don't know that, Anna.
Anger's all I have left in me now.
-Jepoy, please.
-I'm sorry.
-Wait--
-Anna!
You know what?
This is for Nanny Carlotta.
This is for her.
Jepoy!
[dramatic music playing]
I'm sure by now,
you've heard my son's missing.
Yes.
And what are you going to do about it?
And what? Am I supposed
to do something about it?
Yes! Since you're the governor,
you should be concerned
about the Ardientes' welfare.
Linda, call the chief of police
and tell him
to prioritize the search
for Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo.
Thank you.
I knew you wouldn't say no to me.
[foreboding music playing]
[birds chirp]
[inhales]
[exhales]
[tense music playing]
Arnaldo!
You bastard!
[grunts]
-Why did you hurt Anna?
-I don't know--
-What did I ever do to you?
-I don't know you.
Why do you keep hurting the people I love?
-What's with you?!
-I don't know you.
-I don't--
-You don't know me?
[grunting]
I'm going to kill you!
I don't know what you're talking about!
Trust me, I'm clueless.
-Please stop!
-[both grunting]
[Jepoy] This is for Nanny Carlotta!
[Diego] Jepoy!
[Jepoy] Let go of me!
-Stop it!
-Get lost, Diego!
-Hold on!
-I'll kill him!
Hold on! Can you please calm down?!
That man is a murderer!
And his time is up!
It's time to make him pay!
-But we're not murderers!
-Well, he is!
-He's a murderer!
-That's enough, Jepoy!
[suspenseful music playing]
-[Arnaldo] Enough! Stop! Stop!
-I'll kill you!
-Stop it, Jepoy!
-[Jepoy groans]
I'm begging you. Please stop!
I don't know what you're talking about.
[Jepoy grunts]
You don't know?!
You killed our Nanny Carlotta!
I don't know anything! Believe me.
Forgive me for whatever
I did to you, to all of you.
I don't know anything! Forgive me!
Jepoy, enough.
[Arnaldo] I don't know
what you're talking about!
Enough!
I don't remember anything.
I don't remember if I did anything to you.
-You liar!
-Forgive me.
Please, forgive me. I'm begging you.
-Diego, he's lying.
-If I did anything to you,
I wholeheartedly ask for your forgiveness.
I really don't remember anything.
Search every corner of Ardiente.
Find Arnaldo.
-Yes, boss.
-Go.
-Let's go.
-Jaguar.
-Emilia.
I've just dispatched my men.
I had them scour Poblacion Ardiente
to find your son, Arnaldo.
Oh!
I didn't know you were up to date
with the news in Ardiente.
You know I'm always informed
about Ardiente.
Especially about your life.
Aw, Jaguar!
But there seems to be a delay
in your news feed.
Because somebody else
is doing that for me now.
It's Governor Ruiz.
But still, I thank you for your
help. I appreciate it.
Hold on.
What is it you admire
about that governor, anyway?
First of all,
he's just Lily Cruz's lapdog, isn't he?
That's what you think.
What you don't know…
is that Governor Ruiz has a new master.
And you're in front of her.
[chuckles lightly]
But, you know, I believe
in equality among pets.
So, I'll let you fight among yourselves.
Cats versus dogs.
Bye, kitty-kitty. Meow!
Oops! I'm sorry. I mean, Jaguar. Bye-bye!
[Jepoy] Why do you keep butting…
-into everything?
-Jepoy…
-Jepoy! Why are you fighting?
-Huh?
[Jepoy] And how could you believe him?!
-Don't believe him!
-Why are you arguing?
He's just pretending not to remember,
-but he knows every--
-Jepoy.
What is this? What's going on?
Why are you fighting?
Tell her.
Tell her what you did!
Tell her!
I was about to get rid of Arnaldo…
when he got in the way.
I was this close, Diego! This close!
Arnaldo? How did you even get near him?
[tense music playing]
[Mercedes] We've found your son, Arnaldo.
Is he safe?
Yes.
He's under the care
of the Sitio Onse residents.
Yuck!
How can he be safe there
with the poor people?
There's no AC at Sitio Onse.
Mosquitoes will swarm him there!
You have nothing to worry about.
Well, if you say so.
But how did you do that?
Is it because of Governor Mateo?
No, Emilia.
We already knew where Arnaldo was
before you even spoke to Governor Ruiz.
Hmm? How did that happen?
Papa, Mateo, and even
the Jaguar just started.
Because your mother doesn't
belong in the same league
as those boys.
They are all playing in the playground,
while your mother owns it.
Hmm…
Does that mean I get
to own the playground too?
Of course. You are the heir to the throne.
[laughing]
I now love my Mama so much.
[ominous music playing]
Stop staring at each other!
I asked a question!
[tense music playing]
He was at Sitio Onse.
I saw him the other day.
You saw Arnaldo the other day,
and you didn't tell me?
Lily, I didn't want to add
to all the problems--
That I already have?
With a secret
that could cost you your life?
But it was Arnaldo
who almost died, not me!
And I would've killed him
if you didn't stop me, Diego!
He would've been one problem gone!
No matter what you say,
Arnaldo's still my brother!
How many times do I have to
say that we're not criminals…
-like them!
-Your brother's a murderer!
And as long as the Ardientes are around,
our lives are in danger, Diego!
If we don't get ahead of them,
they'll wipe us out!
Use your head! Don't be so naïve!
We are not murderers, Jepoy.
I already told you that.
It must've slipped your mind,
so let me repeat it again.
We are not murderers.
If you kill even just
one of the Ardientes,
we will forever have their blood smeared
on our hands and conscience.
So I hope you get it now.
-Are you sure Arnaldo's here?
-Yes, Papa.
According to my reliable source,
he is really here.
-Reliable source or gossip?
-Huh?
I'm telling you, Emilia.
If you brought me here
only to find nothing,
you're going to be in trouble!
-[Emilia sighs]
-What kind of place is this?
[tense music playing]
Holy sh--
[Julio] What is this?!
Arnaldo?
What happened to you?
Why do you have--
Did someone beat you up?
[stutters] No.
I just fell over. It was an accident.
You have to come home with us.
You are not safe here.
-I won't come with you.
-Huh?
I won't be safer with any of you.
What do you mean?
I found out about your crimes, Grandpa.
All the things you did to the people
of Poblacion Ardiente.
[Julio] What is happening to you?!
Are you even my grandson?!
-Papa!
-Hold on.
No matter what you say,
I'm not going with you!
I was led here to fulfill a mission.
I can't just leave.
Like it or not, you're coming with us.
I'll even have my men drag you
away from here if I have to.
Papa, enough, okay? Let him be.
If he wants to stay here, then go ahead.
Can't you see even the sky's
getting angry?
Now you're afraid of a
little thunder and lightning?
Wait. Arnaldo, are you
going to be fine here?
-[thunder rumbling]
-I am.
All right. If, or when,
you decide to come home,
we're just one call away, okay?
[pensive music playing]
[Julio] Going up here was a waste of time.
Arnaldo, are you sure
you'll be all right here?
-[Julio speaking indistinctly]
-Yes, I'll be okay.
Take care of yourself, okay?
-All right.
-Thanks.
[Julio] Did you hear him?
[Emilia] Yeah.
[somber music playing]
[Anna] Jepoy, sit down.
-Give me your hand.
-[winces]
That hurts!
Are you doing that on purpose?!
Jepoy.
I bet Julio already knows
that Arnaldo's at Sitio Onse.
I got a text from the residents
saying they saw Julio,
but that Arnaldo didn't go with them.
I'm sure they'll force Arnaldo
to go with them soon enough.
It's all up to him.
But then, the Ardientes' enemies
might still go after him.
I was thinking that maybe
we should help him out.
Protect him, even.
Wait.
Did I hear that right?
We're going to protect Arnaldo?
Jepoy, I know it's hard to accept,
but what if he's really changed?
He killed Nanny Carlotta.
So, even Emilia and Julio
can be our friends now?
Well then, why not just
invite them all here?!
For a chat!
[phone ringing]
[foreboding music playing]
[ringing continues]
Hello?
Miss Lily Cruz.
Word on the grapevine
is you're looking for me.
Mercedes Palacio.
[tense music playing]
Yes.
Unfortunately,
this is the closest
you can get to meeting me.
You see, I'm not fond of meeting traitors.
So, is that why you had
all my buildings bombed?
Yes!
And if you don't stop
harassing the Ardientes,
I assure you, your loved ones
will be in grave danger.
Mercedes…
I don't think you really know
just who I am.
I've been to hell and back.
So there's no way
I'll ever be afraid of you.
[tense music swelling]
I can't believe
that we left Arnaldo there.
The lightning, Papa. It would've struck.
You know, this is why your son
ended up like this.
You're weak!
A little trouble, you scream!
A little obstacle
and you pull back right away!
I can stand in the center of this field
with thunder and lightning going off,
and not one lightning bolt will touch me.
Even lightning is scared of me.
You know, Papa, this is all your fault.
If only you were a good grandfather,
then Arnaldo wouldn't
have chosen to stay behind.
I knew it.
Out of all the things
you could've inherited
from your arrogant mother,
it just had to be her thick, empty skull.
Don't insult my mother.
What is it to you if I do?
[Julio] You look like her,
you think like her.
[sighs]
And here's another idiot!
What is it?
[tense music playing]
What is this?
It's simple, Julio Ardiente.
I'm letting you know
that you no longer have power
over this town.
Only your name remains in this place.
And if you are a real man,
you should at least fight fair,
instead of bombing my businesses.
Whoa!
Miss Ivy Aguas, or Lily Cruz,
or whoever you are today,
I may be utterly entertained
by the thought
that your businesses
are going up in flames,
but I have nothing to do with that.
-[Julio] I am not behind it all.
-I'm not stupid!
[tense music continues]
I believe that at least
one of you Ardientes
had something to do with
the bombings of my businesses.
Just to remind you,
and to make sure you never forget.
You know how I fight.
I never back down.
[dramatic music swelling]
Papa, how are we going
to pass through right now?
She left those barricades.
That's easy.
Let her leave.
Let her take her trained
swinging monkeys with her.
Let us talk about Aguas Realty.
Have you seen the headline about it?
Yes, but as far as Aguas Realty
is concerned,
that's yesterday's news.
Before the market closed,
Aguas Realty's stock went up
five points.
That's pretty awesome.
But how can that happen
within the last 24 hours?
Well, it is because
of their CEO, Miss Lily Cruz.
Her immediate response
and fearless leadership
assured the investors' confidence
that all security issues
have been addressed.
-She's really amazing.
-Yes.
I didn't expect Lily Cruz
to recover so quickly.
But don't worry, Madam.
We're working on it.
[phone ringing]
I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
Julio and the Ardientes
really don't seem to know
about Mercedes Palacio.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Miss Cruz, I'm calling
to announce your defeat.
You'll never find me.
I've covered my tracks.
And you never know
when I'm going to strike next.
So, do you concede?
Never.
That woman…
She really did erase any clues
as to where I can find her.
But I won't stop.
I know I'll find her.
Lily, she forgot one thing.
Mylar's still in police custody.
[tense music swelling]
[Mercedes] Emilia.
The time has come.
Your real mother wants to see you.
[suspenseful music playing]
[ethereal music playing]
Hmm.
Is this an early Christmas gift?
My!
Thank you, whoever you are.
[eerie music]
[gasps]
Who sent this?!
[ethereal music playing]
Madam, we've delivered
your present for Julio Ardiente.
Excellent.
[ethereal music playing]
[slow music playing]
[slow music continues playing]
[snaps fingers]
[footsteps approaching]
[dramatic music playing]
[somber music playing]
Mama?
Emilia, my daughter.
[sobs] Mama.
[Lily] Red Dragon is the head
of the biggest prostitution,
smuggling, white slavery,
kidnap-for-ransom,
and terrorist syndicate
here in the Philippines.
But I can't understand
why she'd come after me.
I will eliminate both
your papa and Lily Cruz.
I'll give you back your crown.
You will be the queen of Ardiente.
[Julio] Have you really come back?
Why now?
No one and nothing is gonna
separate us ever again.
And if anyone tries, I will crush them.
[theme music playing]